说明：我是为了学外语才看外语片并选择双语字幕的，本人眼神儿不好，为了自己看着方便才修改。放到网上是避免硬盘数据遗失。就叫：眼神儿不好学外语字幕组吧。
4K字幕来源：www.Hao4k.com
更多4K电影请到www.Hao4k.com 下载
1947年 以色列被联合国承认
以色列国
巴勒斯坦人立刻开始为了他们的故土而抗争
巴勒斯坦人开始抗争
全球各地的左翼革命团体加入了他们
他们一起对以色列平民展开袭击行动
他们自称 自由战士
以色列人称他们为 恐怖分子
火狐一号出击
本片取材于真实事件 对话、事件和人物均为电影化而创作
第一日
1976年 6月27日 星期日
请快点通过
Come. Come through please.
雅典 希腊
快去那边
Move! Over there!
你们听好了 这是劫机
Everybody, this is a hijack situation!
都别动
Nobody move!
-都别动 -如果你们都乖乖坐好
- Nobody move! - If you all stay in your seats
不乱动 那么没人会受伤
and do not move, no one will be harmed.
但要是有人搞小动作 我就引爆这枚手榴弹
But if anybody tries anything, I will throw this grenade.
都别动 乖乖坐好
Nobody move! Everyone stay in your seat!
别动 我手上有炸弹
Don't move! I have a bomb!
后面在吵什么呢
可能是谁掉了根烟吧 我去看看
坐下
Sit down!
Sit! Sit!
我们已经占领了座舱
We've got the cabin under control.
我们四个人
It's four of us.
我们有武器和炸弹
We've got weapons and bombs.
如果你敢耍小花样 你的小命就不保了
If you try anything, you will die.
39 你那控制住没有
Comrade 39, is the cabin secured?
-控制住了 -都给我坐好
- Cabin secured. - Stay in your seats,
什么都别做
and nobody try anything.
你们都快去后舱坐着 快点
Everyone in here, get into the back cabin now. Move!
什么都别带 快走
Take nothing with you. Move, move!
你们谁是机长
Who's the captain?
-我 -你们俩出去
- I am. - You two, out.
我是随机工程师 我得待在这
I'm the flight engineer. I'm-I'm needed here.
你 起来走人
You, up.
都快走
Move! Hurry, hurry!
-快点 -把包放下 走
- Come on. Come on! - Leave your bags. Go!
-快点 -快走
- Faster! - Come on, go!
你也是
And you, too.
好 好 好
Okay, okay, okay.
快点
Faster! Come on!
妈咪 我想上厕所
忍着
如果我们没有几所好学校
If we don't have good schools,
没有完善的医保体系 如果我们
a good health system... if we don't invest
不投资我们自己的文化产业 那我们是在为什么拼搏呢
in our own culture, what are we fighting for?
我们不能把纳税人的钱
We cannot allocate all the taxpayers' money
都投入到你的部门 西蒙
to your ministry, Shimon.
国防部的预算已经占了GDP的百分之三十一了
The defense budget is already 31% of the GDP.
四年就涨了百分之十
A raise of ten percent in four years.
就我个人看来
In my personal assessment,
在军队花销上增长百分之十
a ten-percent increase in military spending
是我们能接受的底线了
is the minimum that we need.
再低那可就是我们的失职了
Anything less would be a dereliction of our duty.
先生们 这可不是我们愿不愿意的问题
Now, this is not about a choice, gentlemen.
这是必须要做的事情
This is compulsory.
这关乎到以色列的存亡
This is about the survival of Israel.
就像赎罪日战争证明的那样
As the Yom Kippur War proved, our intelligence capabilities
我们的情报水平也很低
are also lacking.
我们没有多少陆地财产
We don't have the assets on the ground.
我们需要更多的特工
We need more agents.
我们得靠钱来换来影响力
We need to buy more influence.
俄罗斯已经大大增加了
The Russians have massively increased
对埃及的军事援助
military aid to Egypt.
叙利亚也在准备重新武装
Syria is also re-arming.
戈兰高地那
There are Russian military personnel
从特拉维夫至巴黎的
法航139
在雅典中途停留时被劫机
也有俄罗斯驻扎的军队
back in the Golan Heights.
还不只是坦克和飞机的问题
It is not just tanks and airplanes.
我们的能力也实在欠缺
Also, capabilities are lacking.
如果我们又被人看到防守不足
If we are caught off guard again,
结果可是灾难性的
the consequences will be catastrophic.
飞机上有多少以色列人
劫机犯有几个人
他们要去哪
在我看来 俄罗斯...
In my assessment, Russia...
这是必须要做的
This is compulsory.
这关乎于我们需要的那百分之十军队开销增长
This is about the ten percent that we need.
当我们被敌人追着屁股跑的时候
We cannot allocate money to health and education
我们不能把钱分配到医疗和教育上
when we are being driven into the sea by our enemies.
你们必须把所有
You're required to hand over
能证明你们身份的东西交出来
all documents that give evidence of your identity.
如果谁敢藏着掖着点什么
Anyone who is caught holding back any papers
我们可不会对他手下留情
will be punished without mercy.
所有人都快点
Come on, everyone, give me
把你们的护照和身份证交出来
your passport and I.D. card, too.
护照 护照
Passport. Passport.
护照 身份证
Passport. I.D.
快把你的身份证也给我
Come on, give me your I.D. card, too.
好的
Okay.
护照
Passport.
总理办公室
飞机上共有239名乘客
There are 239 passengers on board.
83个是以色利人
83 are Israeli.
从法律上讲 这是法国人的问题
Legally, it's a French problem.
这是他们的客机 大部分也都是法国人
It's their airliner and mostly their citizens.
如果真发生了劫机 我们得保证
If it's a hijack, we'll make sure
媒体了解到那个情况
the press understands that.
我可以打电话给编辑们
I can call the editors.
就是劫机
It's a hijack.
他们会飞到这挑战我们
They'll fly back here to challenge us.
总是如此
They always do.
阿莫斯 总理啊...
Amos, Prime Minister...
这就是我们的问题
this is our problem.
你的意思是这是我的问题咯 西蒙
You mean it's my problem, Shimon?
妈咪 我真的想上厕所
-呃... -坐下
- Uh... - Sit down.
-不是 我... -坐下
- No, excuse me, but... - Sit down.
我女儿必须得上趟厕所
My daughter really needs to go to the bathroom.
你啊
You?
恩
Yeah.
想上厕所？
You need to go?
快去
Hurry up.
-我也要去 -你就给我坐着吧
- I need to go, too. - You can stay sitting down.
小姐...
Miss...
你的纽扣开了
Your blouse is open.
别想着弄坏起落架
Don't try and break the undercarriage.
要不我们就一起去死
If you do, we'll die together.
别担心 我会平稳着陆的
Don't worry. I'll do a kiss landing.
转个头
Reverse.
好
Check.
好样的 机长
Good, Captain.
班加西 利比亚
怎么要花这么久
Why is this taking so long?
除非你告诉我我们要飞到哪
Unless you tell me where we're going,
否则我得要五六桶才够
I'm going to need five or six of these.
好
Okay.
回飞机里去
Get back inside the plane.
如果你想我们能顺利、安全地起飞
If you want to fly on and if you want to be safe,
我得做一下飞前检查
I-I need to do my pre-flight checks.
我得检查下轮胎 制动器 和引擎
I need to check the wheels, the brakes and the engine.
你得去关心下飞机里那些人
You should be taking care of those people inside.
他们都待五个多小时了
They've been on this plane five hours now.
得吃点喝点什么
They need food and drinks.
你会逃得远远的
You will run.
相信我 我不会
You have my word, I won't.
而且你也不想在
And you don't want to be holding that
油车旁拿着手榴弹
next to a fuel truck.
你是巴德尔·迈因霍夫集团的人吗
Are you a member of Baader-Meinhof?
把油装满 工程师
Fill up the plane, engineer.
别多管闲事
Do your job.
法兰克福 德国
六个月前
贾贝尔
Jaber.
-布丽吉特 这是胡安·帕布洛 -你好
- Brigitte, Juan Pablo. - Hello.
打劫飞机？
Hijacking a plane?
这是一次很重要的行动
That is a serious step.
我们有什么任务吗
What's in it for us?
听听贾贝尔怎么说
Let's just see what Jaber has to say.
请坐
Sit.
你们这次行动压力重重
Your movement is under pressure.
你们的后援力量在减弱
Your support is fading.
许多队友也进了监狱
Many of your colleagues are in jail.
但这次的行动将会激励一批新的追随者
An action like this can inspire a new generation to follow you.
巴勒斯坦人民解放组织将要求释放
The PFLP will call for the release
被捕的五十名巴勒斯坦犯人
of 50 Palestinian prisoners.
我们也可以趁机要求释放我们的同伴
We could also demand the release of some of our friends.
如果我们完成这次任务 我们就可以得到我们想要的一切
If we do this, we can demand anything we want.
我们可以要求释放乌尔丽克·迈因霍夫吗
We can demand that Ulrike Meinhof is on the list?
他们不会释放乌尔丽克的
They will never release Ulrike.
就像我说的那样
Like I said,
如果我们顺利完成这次任务
if we do this right,
他们就不得不满足我们的全部要求
they have to do whatever we want.
也门
巴勒斯坦人民解放组织
瞄准
Aim!
射击
Fire!
博斯
Bose!
我有话和你说
We need to talk.
乌尔丽克死了
Ulrike Meinhof is dead.
她自杀了
She killed herself.
你的行动快结束了
Your movement is dying.
她剪掉了她的头发
She cut her hair.
不仅仅如此 她放弃了一切
No, she quit.
这起事件引出了一个问题
And that poses a problem.
什么问题
Which problem?
他的父亲和母亲
His father and his mother.
妹妹和妻子以及他们的孩子
His sister and his wife, and their children.
当时他们全在黎巴嫩的难民营里
They were all in a camp in Lebanon.
以色列突袭了难民营
The Israelis raided it.
杀死了里面的人 炸毁了房屋
Killed people, dynamited the houses.
他们试图逃跑
They tried to escape.
他们钻进一辆车子里 一个以色列士兵开着坦克撞了上来
They were in a car. An Israeli tank drove over it.
他们就全死了
All of them died.
这就是我所知道的为什么他投入这次复仇行动的原因
That's how I know that he's committed.
现在你的好朋友死了
How do I know that you're committed
你又是为什么加入呢
now your comrades are dead?
她不会上吊自杀的
She would never hang herself.
她是被以色列派人谋杀的
She was murdered by the state.
如果我们回到德国 我们也会被谋杀的
And if we return to Germany, we will be murdered, too.
现在最为关键的是 我们得继续完成这次行动
It's all the more important that we continue.
-为了乌尔丽克 -也为了你失去的家人
- For Ulrike. - And for your family.
贾贝尔将在机场听从指挥
At the airport, Jaber will be in command.
我将留在坎帕拉 和阿明总统保持联络
I will stay in Kampala and liaise with President Amin.
乌干达部队将监控
Ugandans will control the perimeter
机场和建筑周边的情况
of the airfield and the building.
你们全部待在里面
You will all stay inside.
在这种情况下 你们务必得小心
You must be careful in these situations.
而且要和乘客之间保持距离
You must keep your distance from the passengers.
任何的恻隐之心将会十分危险
Emotional attachment can be really dangerous.
尤其是对女人
Particularly for women.
我是一个坚决的革命者
I am a revolutionary.
您要喝点水吗
Would you like some water?
您要给孩子们喝点水吗
Would you like some water for the kids?
您要喝点水吗
Would you like some water?
我感觉不舒服
I don't feel well.
你需要什么吗
What do you need?
我…我怀孕了
I-I'm pregnant.
我感觉我好像流产了
I think I'm having a miscarriage.
-好的 我马上去帮你找位医生 好吗 -好
- Okay, I'm going to try to find you a doctor, okay? - Yeah.
小姐 她身体不舒服
Miss? She doesn't feel well.
她急需一位医生
She really needs to see a doctor.
怎么回事
What is the problem?
她感觉她好像流产了
She thinks she's losing her baby.
也太容易了点 对吧
她可不敢
呃 女士 我是护士
Uh, miss, I'm a nurse.
-或许我可以帮上忙 -你在那别动
- Maybe I can help. - You can wait.
几个月了
Which month?
两…两个月
Two... two months.
你来自哪里
Where you from?
英格兰
England.
我们会叫救护车的
We will call an ambulance.
我们不想伤害任何人
We don't want to hurt anyone.
因为我们是人道主义者
We're humanitarians.
跟我来
Come with me.
他要去哪
我不知道
她在骗你
She's fooling you.
还是有点同情心比较好 兄弟
It's better to show mercy, comrade.
我要流产了
I'm losing my baby.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-不准用无线电 -我们必须
- No radio. - We have to speak
得和航空交通管理人员通话才能获得起飞许可
to air traffic control for clearance.
跑道上没有其他飞机 他们知道我们要离开
The runway's empty. They know we're leaving.
-放下它 -我们需要知道我们……
- Just take off. - We need to know we're...
我让你放下
Take off!
启动引擎
Set thrust.
启动完毕
Set.
利比亚人给飞机加满燃料 再次起飞了
The Libyans refueled them and let them take off again.
卡扎菲也不想这件事成为他的绊脚石
Gaddafi doesn't want this to be his problem, either.
他们加了多少燃料
How much fuel?
至少能飞五个小时
At least five hours.
特维拉夫已在监控范围内
Tel Aviv is in range.
他们将在本·古里安机场着陆
They'll land at Ben Gurion.
他们想让全世界见证他们的行动
They want the world to watch.
还有一件事
There is one other thing.
他们放走了一名乘客
They released a passenger.
飞机上有两个是阿拉伯人和
Uh, there were two Arabs.
巴勒斯坦人
Palestinians, I think.
和两名德国人
And two Germans.
一男一女
A man and a woman.
为什么他们会放你离开
Why did they let you off the plane?
我对他们撒谎了
I lied.
我告诉他们我怀孕了
I told them I was pregnant.
那他们有说他们接下来要去哪里吗
Did they say where they are going?
这整个行动毫无意义
This whole operation is nonsense.
我们从没有提及过要去乌干达
We never talked about going to Uganda.
伊迪·阿明……他绝对是疯了
Idi Amin... he's crazy.
他不仅"吃人"
He eats people.
还拿他们去喂鳄鱼
He feeds them to the crocodiles.
我们把我们的命交给了一个疯子
We're putting our lives in the hands of a lunatic.
一旦我们到达乌干达 我们就安全了
Once we get to Uganda, we are safe.
以色列政府没有选择
The Israelis have no choice.
他们必须得妥协
They have to negotiate.
因为这是将死之局
It's checkmate.
如果他们不愿意谈判怎么办
And what happens if they don't negotiate?
他们……
They...
他们没得选
They have to.
否则我们就杀了人质
Or we kill the hostages.
好吧
Yes.
你将不得不去杀人
You will have to kill people.
德国人杀死犹太人……你想过这个吗
Germans killing Jews... have you thought about that?
乌尔丽克·迈因霍夫因我而死
Ulrike Meinhof is dead because of me.
-并不是这样的 -事实就是如此
- That is not true. - It's true.
我相信了一个本不该信任的人
I trusted someone I shouldn't have,
导致她被逮捕 然后她现在死了
and she was arrested, and now she is dead.
如果你还有迟疑的话……
If you're having doubts...
你应该离开
you should leave.
你舍得我离开吗
Do you want me to leave?
恩德培 乌干达
欢迎来到乌干达 恩德培市
Welcome to Entebbe, Uganda.
我至今还没有
I haven't had the time up until now
对劫持这架法国航空飞机
to explain the reasons
作出解释
for hijacking an Air France plane.
尽管对法国的
Despite the belief of many
亲阿拉伯政策抱有很大希望
that France has a pro-Arab policy,
但法国仍是加入巴勒斯坦敌军的
it is one of the first countries
第一批国家之一
in the rank of Palestinian enemies.
它曾与摩萨德情报局合作
France has cooperated with Mossad.
还向以色列出售飞机
France has sold planes to Israel.
同时法国还在以色列制造原子弹上提供帮助
France has given Israel help in building atom bombs.
巴勒斯坦没有原子弹 没有军队 也没有武器
Palestine has no atom bombs, no army and no weapons.
所以巴勒斯坦人民解放组织
The Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine
必须得利用其他手段，
must utilize other means
去引起世界对巴勒斯坦人民
to focus the attention of the world
艰苦挣扎的现状的关注
on the Palestinian people's struggle.
我们将呼吁全世界的革命运动
We call upon revolutionary movements everywhere
联合起来去对抗以色列
to unite against Israel,
这个法西斯暴政的 犹太复国者的和种族歧视的民族
a fascist, Zionist and racist state.
惨无人道地剥削
Israel has exploited
人民的
the humanistic sentiments of its people
人道主义精神
to inhuman ends.
她完全是纳粹主义的继承者
She's the heir of Nazism.
请你保持冷静
I would ask that you remain calm.
我们不会伤害你的
We will not do you any harm.
我们不是杀手
We are not assassins.
我们不想进行一场毫无意义的屠杀
And we do not want to commit a pointless massacre.
你们今晚会在飞机上度过
You will spend tonight on the plane.
明天我们就到航站楼
Tomorrow, we move to the terminal.
我知道你们有很多航空公司的选择
We know you have a choice of airlines.
多谢你们选择法国航空
Thank you for flying Air France.
期待与你们很快再次相见
We hope to see you again very soon.
现在你们知道
Now you know how the mind
一个疯狂的德国革命派的大脑是怎么运作的了
of a crazy German revolutionary works.
机长
Captain.
打开门
Open the door.
-回去 -小心台阶
- Get back. - Mind the step.
这是降落在这个机场最大的飞机
This is the biggest plane this airport has ever seen.
博尼 你应该来看看听你讲话后
Boni, you should see the faces
这些乘客的脸色
of the passengers after your speech.
怎么了
What?
他们很害怕
They are terrified.
-你说了什么 -你不会想知道的
- What did he say? - You don't want to know.
-嘿 -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
第二日
1976年 6月28日 星期一
欢迎来到乌干达
Welcome to Uganda.
我是阿尔-哈吉阁下
I am His Excellency al-Hajji
元帅、伊迪·阿明·达达博士
Field Marshal Doctor Idi Amin Dada,
英国维多利亚十字勋章的持有人
holder of the British Victoria Cross,
还有DSO、CMV、MC勋章
DSO, CMV, MC,
被全能的上帝任命为你们的救世主
appointed by God Almighty as your savior!
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我是非洲的英雄
I am the hero of Africa.
我也是你们的英雄
And I am your hero.
我们会满足你们的所有需求
We will take care of your every need.
我们也非常希望你们会享受
And we hope very much that you will enjoy
待在在我们这个美丽的国家
your stay in our beautiful country.
所有事情都会被照料到
And everything will be taken care of.
你们会得到很好的照顾
You are in good hands.
请 请 请进
Please, please, step inside.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
来吧
Come on.
希望他们能尽快开始谈判
是啊
Yeah.
我去跟他谈谈
我们做到了
We did it.
做的不错 做的不错
Well done. Well done.
我们什么时候开始谈判
When do we start to negotiate?
放轻松 同志
Relax, comrade.
你做得很好
You've done a good job.
现在轮到我们了
It's up to us now.
而且我们很了解以色列人
And we know the Israelis very well.
我们知道他们怎么思考
We know how they think,
他们怎么行动 怎么工作
how they operate, how they work.
我们将着手谈判工作
We will handle the negotiations.
如果你有任何问题的话和贾贝尔谈 贾贝尔
If you have any problems, just talk to Jaber. Jaber.
你的任务是看紧这些乘客
Your job is to watch the passengers.
你们两个
Both of you.
4000千米
4,000 kilometers.
从来没有人能把飞机劫持的这么远
No hijacker has ever taken a plane this far away
在我们军队的部署范围内
from the operational sphere of our armed forces.
这肯定是哈达德干的
It must be Haddad.
总理 你不能屈服
Prime Minister, you can't give in,
否则任何成为目标的以色列人
or every Israeli they target
将会被胁迫去另一个国家
will be taken to another country.
国防部长 你的任务是策划
Defense Minister, your job is to come up
前往非洲的军事行动
with military options for going to Africa.
一旦你有一个可行方案 我会决定来做什么
Once you have a viable one, I'll decide what to do.
有什么问题吗？
Any questions?
阿莫斯将协调成立一个紧急委员会
Amos will coordinate an emergency committee.
当我们收到劫机者的要求时 我们会再见面的
As soon as we get the demands, we will meet again.
你知道 这不是佩雷斯的问题
You know, this is not Peres' problem.
你才是整个政府的门面
It's your face on the front of every newspaper.
如果是哈达德的话 他会要求
If it's Haddad, he's going to demand
我们释放监狱里的所有恐怖分子
the release of every terrorist in our jails.
你不能释放他们
Well, you can't release them.
那将会是政治自杀
That's political suicide.
我知道
I know that.
这鳄鱼不错
我觉得我们该试着跟我们的德国“首领”谈谈
我们不能跟这种人谈判
也许我们能看穿他们脑子里想的什么
你该吃点东西
我不饿
我想我得跟他谈谈
你确定？
接下来要怎么办
How is this going to work?
这地方很脏 我们还有孩子
This place is filthy. We got children here.
我会打扫干净的
I'll have it cleaned.
然后他们会提供床垫
And they'll bring mattresses.
一切都会好起来的
It's all going to be fine.
别担心
Don't worry.
我为什么要相信一个疯狂的德国革命派
Why should I believe a crazy German revolutionary?
一切都会搞清楚的
Everything will become clear.
一切
Everything.
把灯打开
Turn it back on.
你睡觉时还亮着灯吗？
Do you still sleep with your lights on?
回去睡觉
Go to bed.
他们在数有多少以色列护照
是啊
Ja.
我们得知道这些乘客都是谁
睡觉吧
以色列是一个法西斯国家
Israel is a fascist state,
真正的反法西斯意味着
and true anti-fascism means clear and simple solidarity
和巴勒斯坦人简单明了的团结
with the Palestinians.
别再喊这些口号了
Stop quoting these slogans.
德国人劫持了一整个飞机的以色列人
Germans hijacking a planeload of Israelis.
还有犹太人 你们觉得全世界会有怎样的反应
Jews. How do you think the world's going to react?
你知道的 我们会面临的唯一事实就是
You know, the only thing that we have to face is the fact
德国人不会分析
that German people cannot analyze
近东的争端
the conflict in the Near East
因为我们都被愧疚麻痹了
because we are all paralyzed by guilt.
西德是一个法西斯社会 胡安·帕布洛
West Germany is a fascist society, Juan Pablo.
也许你看来并不是这样
Perhaps it doesn't appear so to you,
但对那些掌权人都是一样的
but those who are in charge are the same ones
那些曾经在纳粹手下掌权的人
who were in charge under Nazism.
他们的愧疚给以色列
And their guilt has provided the funds
提供了发展成
which have allowed Israel to develop
一个帝国主义军事基地的资金
into an imperialist military base.
我们不能只读这些书
We can't just read these books.
我们需要去成为他们所代表的东西
We need to become them.
湮灭是属于青少年的词
Annihilation is for adolescents.
我们有革命的权利
There's a right of revolution
去反对政治压迫和社会不公
against political oppression and social injustice.
你没有被压迫 你有工作的
You are not oppressed. You have a business.
我们有革命的权利去反对资本主义
There's a right of revolution against capitalism.
你就是个资本家
You are a capitalist.
我们都是资本家
A bourgeois. We all are.
如果这就是你所想的 那我们需要去行动
If that is what you think, then we have to act,
我们现在就需要行动
and we have to act now.
我不知道你在害怕什么 胡安·帕布洛
I do not know what you are scared of, Juan Pablo.
我什么都不害怕
I'm not scared of anything.
但是你应该害怕
But maybe you should be.
我只怕毫无意义的生活
I only fear a life without meaning.
我在哪
需要帮助吗 女士
Can I help you, madam?
很抱歉 我不会说德语
I'm sorry, I don't speak German.
试试 试着呼吸
Just try... try to breathe.
帮帮我
现在 听着
Now, listen.
帮帮我
不 不
No, no.
不 拜托 请不要这样做
No, please... please don't do that.
拿着
别这样 你想做什么
No, wh-what are you doing?
别这样
No.
请不要伤害我
好的 没事的 放轻松
Okay. It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
我、我不太明白你在说什么 但
Please. I-I don't understand what you're saying, but...
听着 请冷静下来
Listen. Please calm down.
请保持冷静 冷静
Just calm down. Calm down.
我不明白她在说什么
I don't understand what she's saying.
发生什么了
没事 你不用给我们钱
放好 我们不要你的钱 跟我来
跟我来
两个德国人
Two Germans.
是的
Yes.
你说过
You said.
他们将参与革命
They'll be revolutionaries.
七个小时了 还没有消息
Seven hours now, no news.
这次有点奇怪
This time, it's different.
他们都在工作中 伊扎克
They are doing what they are doing, Yitzhak.
你现在什么也做不了
There is nothing you can do about it.
多睡会吧
Get some sleep.
别担心
一切都会好的
任何救援部队
Any rescue force
都要悄无声息的接近老航站楼
would have to approach the old terminal unnoticed.
我们可以用大力神运输机
Look, we can put the men on a Hercules
以色列军事情报局
然后在晚上降落
and land at the airport at night.
-没有跑道灯？ -是的、
- Without runway lights? - Yeah.
很棒
That's great.
我认为拉宾不会同意的
I don't think Rabin will go for that.
那如果我们空投一小队伞兵呢
What if we drop a small parachute force instead?
呃 伞兵的话
Uh, parachute force
在一个地区太分散了
would be dispersed over too large an area.
那我们可以通过维多利亚湖
So we could use Lake Victoria.
要么空降后晚上乘气垫船进去
Either parachute in with inflatable boats at night,
要么通过肯尼亚
or cross from Kenya.
埃胡德 维多利亚湖有鳄鱼的
Ehud, there are crocodiles in Lake Victoria.
而且横跨整个湖也不可能
Plus, it's impossible to come all the way across the lake
从肯尼亚乘无人注意的橡胶船接近老航站楼
from Kenya in rubber boats unnoticed.
这不是演习 好吗？
This is not a drill, okay?
这是真实的作战
It's the real world.
莫塔 为什么我们不让突击队
Motta, why don't we send in the commandos,
占领机场 然后等候伊迪·阿明的消息
take the airport, and then wait to hear from Amin?
呃
Well...
如果你想控制机场
if you want to take control of the airport,
你需要派遣一支大得多的部队
you're gonna have to use a much bigger force.
你能给我一些具体的数字吗？
Could you run some numbers for me?
明天我想要提出一个计划
I want to present a plan tomorrow.
然后 呼叫特殊部队到基地来
Also, call special forces unit to base.
当然 国防部长
Of course, Defense Minister.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
No problem.
我想我知道拉宾为什么要让莫塔来了
I think I know why Rabin wanted Motta here.
他想要阻止我们规划出
He wants to stop us from coming up
一个可行的军事行动
with a viable military option.
那样他就不需要做决定了
That way, he doesn't have to make a decision.
他想把这场危机归咎于你
He wants to blame you for this crisis.
这就是政治
That's politics.
你知道吗 我真希望我也能做到
You know, I wish I could do that.
来了一个电话
There was a phone call.
他们希望你明天回到基地
They want you back at base tomorrow.
什么时候首演
When is the premiere?
跟它无关
It's not about that.
你知道我没有选择的 对吧？
You know I have no choice here, right?
萨拉 我必须去 这是我的工作
Sarah, I have to go. It's my job.
总归是有其他选择的
There's always a choice.
你说错了
That's not true.
那些人质有什么选择？
What choice do those hostages have?
如果你觉得自己没有选择
If you think you have no choice,
那你也是一名人质
you're a hostage, too.
第三日
1976年 6月29日 星期二
特殊任务总部
萨拉
Sarah.
跳舞 就像生活
Dancing, it's like life.
你受伤了 退缩了 没关系
You get hurt, you retract. That's okay.
但是如果你变得如此害怕 总想被保护
But if you become so afraid that you're always guarded
永远不冒险
and never take a leap of faith,
你就永远不会跳舞
you won't be able to dance.
再来一次
Again.
从头开始
From the beginning.
是的
Ja.
听着
Listen.
这儿的所有人 站起来
All of you over here, stand up.
每个人 合上你的书 放下你的牌
Everyone, close your books, put your cards down.
-到走的时候了 –到这里来
- It's time to move now. - And come over here.
-快点 快点 –你必须……我们需要你
- Come on, hurry up. - You have to... we need you
拿上你所有的东西 到那边去
to take all your belongings, move over there.
-搬着椅子 全都拿着 –很好
- Move the chairs, everything. - It's all good.
-很好 –快走 快走 快走
- It's all good. - Move, move, move.
-谢谢你 –有秩序地走 那件夹克？
- Thank you. - Move off in an orderly way. And the jacket?
那是谁的夹克？把所有东西都拿走
Whose jacket is that? Please move everything.
-不要留下任何东西 -听着 我们这么做
- Leave nothing behind. - Listen, we're doing this
是为了制造更多的空间 很好
to create more space. It's all good.
这里太挤了
It's too crowded in here.
明白吗？
Okay?
听到你自己名字的时候 站起来
When you hear your name, you stand up,
到这儿拿着你的护照到另一个房间去
come collect your passport and go to the other room.
阿尔玛格 艾泽拉
Almog, Ezra.
科恩 帕斯科
Cohen, Pasco.
来吧 来吧
Come on, come on.
快 快 快 过来
Fast, fast, fast. Come here.
斯坦伯格 马克
Steinberg, Mark.
艾布拉姆斯 伊萨克
Abrams, Isaac
我们没同意过这个
-放松点
-都是放屁 他们在骗我们
鲁本斯 迈克尔
Rubens, Michael.
你的巴勒斯坦人民解放组织护照
Your Front for the Liberation of Palestine passport.
-琼 拉蒂斯 –穿过这个洞
- June, Ladis. - Go through the hole.
打开你的包 打开你的包
Open your bag. Open your bag.
伯格曼 阿伦
Bergman, Aaron.
快点 快点
Hurry up. Hurry up.
这叫什么事
What is this?
所有人
Everybody.
来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on, come on, come on.
布洛赫 朵拉
Bloch, Dora.
科恩 汉娜
Cohen, Hanna.
不 不好意思 不不 我…我有孩子
No. Uh, excuse me. No, no, I-I have children.
我不能离开我的孩子们
I can't leave my children.
-快点 快点！ -我必须抗议这样做
- Hurry up. Hurry up! - I must protest at this.
不 你们不能这样做 这是错的
No, you can't be doing this. This is wrong.
-她不能离开她的孩子 –不可能离开 –喂！喂！
- She can't leave her children. - It's impossible. - Hey, hey!
闭嘴！坐下！
Shut up! Sit!
还动！坐下！
Move! Down!
坐下！坐下！闭嘴！
Down! Down! Shut up!
我们不同意这样做
We didn't agree to this.
-看住乘客们 –我不是纳粹
- Watch the passengers. - I'm not a Nazi.
-看住乘客！ -喂！坐下！喂！
- Watch the passengers! - Hey! Sit down! Hey!
我想和哈达德谈谈
I want to talk to Haddad.
-以后再谈 –我们得现在谈
- Later. - We talk about this now.
-我们现在就谈谈这事！ -看住乘客们！
- We talk about this now! - Watch the passengers.
我们以后再说
We'll talk about this later.
现在 他妈的把嘴闭上 所有人！
Now, shut the fuck up, all of you!
任何想要反抗我的人都会被枪毙
Anyone who tries to resist me will be shot.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
所有人 继续
All of you. Now.
哈图 伊兰
Hartuv, Ilan.
下一个
Next.
梅耶 萨拉
Mayet, Sala.
梅耶 亚伯拉罕
Mayet, Abraham.
埃尔贝 莫瑞斯
Elbaz, Maurice.
乌曼 丽贝卡
Ullman, Rebecca.
以色列人？
Israeli?
你为什么有法国护照和以色列身份证？
Why do you have French passport and Israeli I.D. card?
噢 我…我是法国公民
Well, I-I'm a French citizen.
我在以色列工作
I was working in Israel,
所以 呃 我拿到了那张
and, uh, I've got that I.D. card,
和我护照一起交上去的身份证
which I handed in with my passport.
你是士兵
You are soldier.
不 我是法国人 我 呃……
No, I'm French. I, uh...
你是间谍
You are spy.
等等 不 我是法国公民
Wait. No, I-I'm a French citizen.
过来吧
All right.
-快走 快走！ -好
- Move. Move! - Okay.
他是法国人
He's French.
他是你朋友？
He is your friend?
-对 –那你也去那边
- Yes. - Then you go through there, too.
为了这项计划的成功
For this plan to succeed,
我们必须动用足够的军事力量
we need to use a big enough force
来夺取机场的控制权
to seize control of the airport.
首先 我们动用突击队员 杀死恐怖分子
First, we use the commandos, kill the terrorists,
确保人质安全
secure the hostages.
然后我们空运增援部队
Then we fly in reinforcements.
包括重型武器 至少1000个士兵
Heavy weaponry, at least 1,000 men.
西蒙 你要入侵乌干达？
You want to invade Uganda, Shimon?
哦 我们离开的时候再还给他们
Oh, we give it back to them when we leave.
我们不能入侵一个联合国
We cannot invade a country that is a member
和及非洲联盟成员国
of the UN and the African League.
并且运输这么大规模的部队是不可能的
And it's impossible to move a force of that size
4000公里的秘密潜入
4,000 kilometers undetected.
我们必须行动
We have to act.
绝不与恐怖分子谈判
There can be no negotiations with terrorists.
我正在和参谋长谈话 西蒙
I'm talking to the chief of staff, Shimon.
军人 而不是政客
The soldier, not the politician.
我必须同意总理的意见
I have to agree with the prime minister.
我们需要查出阿明 是否在帮助他们
We need to find out if Amin is helping them.
你去过乌干达 对吧？你和他打过交道？
You were in Uganda, right? You dealt with him?
我训练过他的军队 是的
I trained his army, yes.
我宁愿假设他不会向法国宣战
I'd like to assume he's not gonna declare war on France.
话虽如此 这人绝对是疯了
Having said that, the man is absolutely crazy.
他可能有想法 某种野心
He might have a dream, some kind of a vision,
任何事都有可能发生
and anything can happen.
我可以试着打给他
I can try... call him.
如果阿明 在恐怖分子一边
If Amin is on the terrorists' side,
我们可能不得不进行谈判
we may have to negotiate.
总理 他们要求释放52名恐怖分子
Prime Minister, they are asking for 52 terrorists.
以色列人不能投降 决不
Israel cannot capitulate. It cannot.
他们后天起将开始
They're going to start killing the hostages
杀害人质
the day after tomorrow.
打给阿明
Call Amin.
我想知道他的立场
I want to know where he stands.
总统官邸
他们已经把犹太人集中
They have moved the Jews together
在恩德培老航站楼了
at the old terminal at Entebbe.
他们用烈性炸药把人质集中起来
They have surrounded them with high explosives.
在飞机上和航站楼周围都有TNT炸药
They have TNT on the plane and all around the building,
甚至他们身上也有
even on their bodies.
他们说他们将与人质一起自杀
They said that they will commit suicide with the hostages.
告诉你们政府 我无能为力
Tell your government there is nothing I can do.
但是 阁下 这是在你们国家
But, Your Excellency, this is your country.
你有一个机会
You have an opportunity
作为英雄被载入史册
to go down in history as a great man.
救了那些人质的英雄
The man who saved these people.
这是一个上帝赐予你的
This is a-a great opportunity, sir,
极好的机会
given to you by God.
那些恐怖分子想要你们
All the terrorists want is for you
把你们的囚犯送到这里来
to send your prisoners here.
不要听坐在那你旁边的巴勒斯坦人民解放组织的人
Don't listen to those from the PFLP sitting beside you.
你在冒犯我 老朋友
You are offending me, old friend.
我试图做的就是
All I'm trying to do
确保人质安全
is make sure the hostages are safe.
很抱歉 阁下
I'm sorry, Your Excellency,
但是请考虑一下我说的话
but please consider what I'm saying.
不要错过这个机会
Don't miss this opportunity
向那些说你坏话的人展现
to show the people who say bad things about you
您是个多么伟大的人
what a great man you are.
实际上 我…我想这会
Actually, I-I think this will
使你获得诺贝尔和平奖的
get you the Nobel Prize for peace.
呃 阁下？
Uh, Y-Your Highness?
阁下？
Y-Your Highness?
为什么巴勒斯坦人民解放组织想要我们
Why would the PFLP want us
把他们的囚犯送到乌干达？
to fly their prisoners to Uganda?
我认为这是阿明的主意 不是巴勒斯坦人的
I think that's Amin, not the Palestinians.
人质被释放的时候他想在场
He wants to be there when the prisoners are released.
他想告诉苏联人和阿拉伯人
He wants to show the Soviets and the Arabs
现在他和他们是一伙的
that he is with them now.
他想获得他们的认同 他们的支持 他们的武器
He wants their approval, their support, their arms.
还有500万块钱
The $5 million.
如果乌干达人与恐怖分子达成一致
If the Ugandans are with the terrorists,
麻烦就更大了
this operation will have to be even bigger.
我和基辛格谈过
I spoke to Kissinger.
他说人质都死了
He said it's better if everybody dies
也比我们谈判要好
than we negotiate.
好吧 如果这跟法国没什么关系
Yeah, well, if it's not a French problem,
那它更不关美国什么事  西蒙
then it's even less of an American problem, Shimon.
我们就尽自己所能吧
Let's do the only thing we can do.
不 请等一下
No, wait. Please.
伊扎克
Yitzhak.
西蒙 我跟你解释下目前的情况
Shimon, let me explain the situation as it stands.
我们没有情报
We have no intelligence.
我们只知道人质在旧航站楼里
We only know the hostages are in the terminal.
其他什么都不知道
Nothing else.
如果他们昨晚把人质转移了呢
What if they moved them around last night?
如果现在有人
What if now we have people sitting
正拿着枪和手榴弹坐他们中间呢
in the middle of them with guns and grenades?
一旦他们知道我们正在接近
As soon as they know we're coming,
他们就会开始杀戮  男人... 女人... 小孩...
they start to kill the men, the women, the children.
所以他们在挑着犹太人 而你只想着谈判
So they are selecting Jews, and you want to negotiate.
西蒙...
Shimon...
如果我们不谈判   如果我们永远都不谈判
if we don't negotiate, if we never negotiate,
如果我们总是处在战争状态
if we're always at war,
那我们就会把我们的国家变成一座监狱
then we will make our country a prison,
每个人都是囚犯
and every one of our citizens will be a prisoner.
我们的敌人就是我们的邻居
Our enemies are our neighbors.
我们不可能摆脱他们
We can't get away from them.
总有一天 我们要为了和平而谈判
One day, we have to talk and to make peace.
谢谢 先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
他们怎么知道你在这
How did they know you were here?
他猜的吧
He guessed.
神灵警告过我的母亲
The spirits warned my mother
我不应该冒犯以色列人
I should never offend the Israelis.
我们应该听我母亲的
We should listen to my mother.
什么意思
To your mother?
先放一些人质
Release some of the hostages.
这样可以安抚法国人
It will appease the French
也能让我们的计划更顺利
and make things easier at the airport.
我不觉得他是间谍
他们在折磨他
我来这不是当保安的
别抱怨了
他们把我们往局外挤
他们总是忽视我
在维也纳和石油输出国组织一起的时候
卡洛斯没选我
我不只是个卖书的
你卖书都卖不好
你得对他们宽容点
你也太宽容了
他们不需要理解我们 他们觉得我们是纳粹分子
他们是犹太人 我们是德国人
他们当然觉得我们是纳粹分子
不然你以为呢？
期望他们理解我们？
当个纳粹 他们至少还会害怕
放屁
我才不假扮纳粹
操你妈
安静点
他妈的
Scheisse.
你已经吃三次了
自从我们来这你就没睡过
我自己来
这
再吃一颗
好样的
这儿
Here.
这就是阿明的车
This is Idi Amin's car.
现在 乌干达的所有官员
Now, all the officials in Uganda
都用一辆黑色的梅赛德斯豪华轿车代步
use a black Mercedes limousine.
嗯
Right.
如果我们用这个接近旧航站楼
If we approached the terminal in one,
恐怖分子可能会认为是阿明
the terrorists would think Amin
来和人质交谈
is coming to talk to the hostages.
这样给了我们一个机会制造“惊喜”
That gives us the element of surprise.
给我一辆奔驰 我们会完成这个任务
Get me a limo there, we'll get the job done.
本尼
Benny?
你怎么看
What do you think?
我们可以把奔驰放在大力士运输机里
We can put the Mercedes in a Hercules
还有特种部队人员
with Sayeret Matkal,
飞机会停在新航站楼
land the plane at the new terminal.
- 嗯 - 他们可以开着奔驰
- Good. - They drive the Mercedes
去旧航站楼杀死恐怖分子
to the old terminal, kill the terrorists,
把人质安放在飞机里 然后飞回来
put the hostages on a plane, fly back.
- 很好 - 现在 为了做到这一步
- Perfect. - Now, to do that,
我们需要控制整个区域
we need to control the whole area.
两个航站楼都要控制
Both terminals.
那你需要什么
And what do you need?
三个小队...
Three companies of soldiers...
丹... 拜托了
Dan, please.
两个小队
Two companies of soldiers,
还有装甲和重型武器
armor and heavy weapons.
- 那得要四驾飞机 - 对 快速行动
- That will be four planes. - Right. Move fast.
所有单位要保持警惕
Keep all units on alert.
拉宾已经和法国人协商过了
Rabin is already talking to the French.
好的 我们有新任务了 快来
Okay, we have new orders. Come down.
走吧
Let's go.
第四日
1976年 6月30日 星期三
好 好
Yes, yes.
请上车
Please.
祝你们旅途愉快
We wish you a pleasant journey.
快来上车 快上车
Come and enter the bus. Enter the bus.
当你们到达目的地的时候
And when you arrive at your destination,
请告诉他们
please tell them
乌干达总统保障了你们的安全
that the president of Uganda guaranteed your safety.
啊 修女 我是你的朋友
Ah. Mother, I'm your friend.
- 请为我们祈祷 - 我不想走
- Please say a prayer for us. - I don't want to leave.
我想把我的座位让给那些
I would like to offer my place to one of the Israeli people
被挟持的以色列人民
who are being held.
那是不可能的
That will not be possible.
我没打算走
I am not going to go.
请上车
Please get inside the bus.
不 我不打算走
No, I'm not going to go.
她糊涂了
She's confused.
快帮她上车
Please help her get inside the bus.
- 不 我要留下来 - 帮她上车
- No. I'm going to stay. - Help her.
- 让她上车 - 上车吧 女士
- Help her. - Get in, madam.
- 不 我..我想留下来 - 上去 快上车
- No, I-I want to stay. - Get in. Get in.
求你了 我..我想留下来
Please. I-I want to stay.
- 拜托了 - 上车
- Please. - Get in.
沙罗
Shalom.
恐怕我不是来带来好消息的
I am afraid I'm not the bearer of glad tidings.
我保证我会尽我所能
I promised I would do everything in my power
让你们被放出去
to have you released.
但是他们还没有收到你们政府的消息
But they haven't heard from your government yet.
最后期限是24小时
The deadline is 24 hours away.
我很担心你们
I'm very worried about you.
这些人与你们无冤无仇
These men bear no grudge against you.
他们只恨你们法西斯式的以色列政府
Only against your fascist Israeli government.
但是如果你们的政府不谈判的话
But if your government do not negotiate,
他们会杀死两个孩子
they will kill two children
每24小时
every 24 hours.
就从这两个孩子开始
Starting with these two.
你怎么能做得到
How can you do this?
拿着你的机枪站在这里
Standing here with your machine gun.
他们还都是些小孩子
These are little children.
我们有士兵
We have soldiers.
如果你想要战斗 去找我们的士兵
If you have to fight, you fight our soldiers.
我不想喝咖啡
I don't want a coffee.
齐夫 你有个电话
Zeev, you have a phone call.
真希望首演的时候我能在
Just wish I could be there.
你不能来吗？
You can't make it?
我克服恐惧了
I got the part I wanted.
嘿 那很好啊
Hey, that's great.
我为你感到高兴
I'm happy for you.
你会安全吗
Will you be safe?
别谈这个
Don't want to talk about that.
你有一直想我吗
Have you been thinking of me?
没 我的意思是.. 你知道..
No, I mean, you know, it...
萨拉  有时候 你爱的人...
Sarah, people you love, sometimes...
想着你爱的人 嗯...其实...
thinking of them, it, um...
没什么用
it doesn't help.
是啊
Yeah.
知道了
I know what you mean.
你在射击场练射击了吗
Have you been practicing on your shooting range?
练了
Yes.
每天都在练
Every day.
很好
Good.
谁的电话
Who was that?
我女朋友
It was my girlfriend.
她是军人吗
Is she in the military?
不 她不是
No, she's not.
如果你想和她在一起
If you want to be with her,
你得让她参军
you need to get her to join the army.
否则 你最好离她远点
Otherwise, it's better you leave her alone.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
字面意思
I mean exactly what I said.
相信我 有经验
Trust me, I know.
巴勒斯坦的劫机人员
The Palestinian hijackers
释放了48名人质乘客
released 48 of their hostage airline passengers.
但他们紧张地拿着机枪站在
But they stood nervously holding machine guns
剩下的209名人质身边  威胁着要杀死他们
on the remaining 209 and threatened to kill them all
炸毁法国客机
and to blow up the French airliner
除非以色列政府满足他们的要求
unless their demands are met.
放走的48名乘客是去巴黎的
The 48 passengers they let go left for Paris,
不久前刚刚抵达
where they arrived a short time ago.
约翰·帕尔玛那时候在机场
John Palmer was there at the airport.
奥利机场的VIP休息室
The VIP lounge here at Orly Airport
已经被警方封锁
has been cordoned off by police,
里面的等候室
and the waiting room inside
挤满了人质的亲属和朋友
crowded with many relatives and friends
等着接回新释放的人质
waiting to greet the newly released hostages.
当然 这些人质都在这架飞机上
Many of them, of course, all of them on this flight,
他们想着能活下来可真幸运
consider themselves very lucky indeed to be alive.
第五日
1976年 7月1日 星期四
借过一下
Excuse me.
怎么了
不知道 什么都用不起 没水 厕所也坏了
肮脏的德国人
你必须知道你们做的事对世界其他地方的影响
You must know how this looks to the rest of the world.
是
Yeah.
我知道会产生什么影响
I know how this looks.
但影响是影响 现实是现实
But it's not the reality.
我不对我同胞的行为负责任
I'm not responsible for the actions of my compatriots.
你在重蹈他们的覆辙
You are repeating their actions.
不 我不是 我不是剥削者
No, I'm not. I'm not the oppressor.
我认为巴勒斯坦人民应当拥有权利
I believe in the rights of the Palestinian people.
他们失去了家园
They have no homeland.
你去过巴勒斯坦难民营吗?
Have you ever seen a Palestinian refugee camp?
你见过人们是如何苟活的吗?
Have you seen how these people live?
你见过他们的孩子吗?
Have you seen their children?
所以为了他们你愿意
So, for them, you are willing
消灭下面那些人?
to exterminate those people down there?
我们得帮他们
We have to help them.
你是干什么的? 做什么工作?
What do you do? What's your job?
你不是士兵
You're not a soldier.
我是出版商
I'm a publisher.
我出版革命书籍
I publish revolutionary texts.
你有没有出版过关于通管道的书?
Have you ever published any books about plumbing?
还没有
Not yet.
尊严...
Dignity...
是众之所望
is all people want.
唯有获得自由才能取得尊严
Dignity comes when you're free.
自来水使你获得自由
Running water makes you free.
厕所...
Toilet...
让你获得自由
makes you free.
一个水管工抵十个革命家
One plumber is worth ten revolutionaries.
你有没有想过你是在浪费生命
Do you ever think you're wasting your life?
没有
No.
你呢?
Do you?
我是个工程师
I'm an engineer.
我能制造物品
I can make things.
一个工程师抵50个革命家
One engineer is worth 50 revolutionaries.
我不想让博斯单独跟乘客待着
他变得越来越大意了
他觉得这一切都是游戏
如果你被困着跟他一起站岗 这就不是游戏了
你一晚上都得听他唠叨
世界的革命
巴勒斯坦的革命
一直不停
你觉得以色利人会来吗
我们已经把他们逼入绝境了
如果他们来了 那杀死他们对不对呢
他们杀了我的孩子
贾贝尔 这什么情况?
Jaber. What is this?
度假营吗?
A holiday camp now?
他们是孩子 哈里曼
They are children, Halima.
以色列政府
The pressure on
所面临的压力是巨大的
the Israeli government was tremendous,
尤其是来自国民的压力
especially from within the country.
以色列人质的亲属
Relatives of the Israeli hostages
于今天上午
held an emotional meeting
和政府代表举行了会晤
with government representatives this morning.
他们不在乎以色列的一个基本国策
They didn't care that Israel has a basic policy
那就是不和恐怖分子做交易
of not dealing with terrorists.
今天早晨
Late in the morning,
他们冲进了政府大楼
they stormed the government compound,
击垮了军事警察
overwhelming military police,
试图找到总理拉宾
in an effort to get at Prime Minister Rabin
并告诉他他们的想法
and tell him what they thought.
我们诉求结果! 我们不能把他们留在那儿!
We want answers! We cannot leave them there!
家属想让我们释放人质
The families want the hostages released.
但作为一个以色列政客
But as an Israeli politician,
你不能和恐怖分子谈判
you can't afford to negotiate with terrorists.
对
That's right.
这成就了我
That's what I've become.
总理!
Prime Minister!
拉宾总理!
Prime Minister Rabin!
我们想和总理交谈
We want to speak with the prime minister.
-停! -我们要求和总理交涉!
- Stop! - We want to speak with the prime minister.
他欠我们一个解释
He owes us an explanation.
我们想见总理
We want to see the prime minister.
等着
Wait here.
所有人 安静
Everybody, calm down.
我们想要一个解释!
We need an explanation!
大使先生 我是总理
Mr. Ambassador, this is the prime minister.
你去告诉法国政府
I would like you to tell the French
我们将和恐怖分子做交易
that we're going to make an offer to the terrorists.
让人震惊的是 以色列人今天
To everyone's surprise, the Israelis today
改变了一贯的政策
reversed their normal policy
并同意和劫持者进行谈判
and agreed to negotiate with the hijackers.
劫持者将截止日期延迟至星期日上午8时
The hijackers put off their deadline to 8:00 a.m. Sunday
就在以色列打破长期政策
after Israel broke its long-standing policy
并同意谈判之后
and agreed to negotiate.
以色列的意见分歧
The difference of opinion in Israel
并不在于是否释放人质
is not over whether the hostages should be released,
而在于从监狱释放恐怖分子
but over whether releasing terrorists from jail here
的代价是否过高
is too high a price to pay for it.
今晚 西墙和众多犹太教堂
Tonight, a special series of prayers began
进行了一系列特别的祷告
at the Western Wall and at most synagogues.
祈祷政府能够
Prayers which expressed the hope that the government
对谈判做出正确的决定
made the right decision on the negotiations
以及以色列和犹太人的人质
and that the Israeli and Jewish hostages
会从乌干达安全返回
will indeed come out of Uganda safely.
我们成功了
真的成功了
能做成功这种任务真是难以想象
贾博认为他们在耍花招
不是花招
我们会改写历史的
我们再也没法回家了
现在还不能
不 是永远不能了
你觉得巴格达怎么样
你完全不会明白一个女人在那里活着会有多艰难
阿拉伯人都是社会主义者
换班了
-你到底在搞什么? -什么?
- What the hell are you doing? - What?
你把你的枪忘在了墙上
You left your gun lying on the wall.
犹太人有可能会拿走呢
One of the Jews could have picked it up.
放轻松 伙计 以色列人已经投降了
Relax, man. The Israelis have surrendered.
他们还没有投降
They have not surrendered.
要是这是一个陷阱怎么办?
What if this is a trick?
要是他们只是以此来拖延时间呢?
What if they are buying more time?
-我们得做好准备 -好的 好的
- We have to be ready. - Okay, okay.
你在这儿做什么?
Why are you here?
我想在群众中
I want to throw bombs
来一个'炸弹'般的头脑风暴
into the consciousness of the masses.
如果你得扔一个真的炸弹呢 我的朋友?
And what if you have to throw a real bomb, my friend?
你杀过人吗?
Have you killed?
你觉得你能做到?
You think you can do it?
你选择拿起武器来战斗
You choose to pick up arms and fight.
你选择来到这里
You choose to come here.
你本可以在欧洲过上美好地生活
You could have a nice life in Europe.
我希望我能过你那样地生活
I wish I had your life.
我就不会拿起武器
I would not pick up a gun.
只有一无所有的人才会理解
Only people with nothing understand.
犹太人能够理解
The Jews understand.
当德国人屠杀他们时
When your people massacred them,
幸存者一无所有
the ones who survived had nothing.
他们将死亡带到巴勒斯坦
They brought their dead to Palestine.
他们带来了羞耻和屈辱
They brought their shame and humiliation.
他们对我们做了他们所受的一切
They did what was done to them to us.
但我没有对他们这样做
But I didn't do it to them.
你对他们这样做了
You did it to them.
你来到这里只是因为你恨你的国家
You are here because you hate your country.
我来这里是因为我爱我的国家
I'm here because I love mine.
你做好杀人的准备了吗?
Are you ready to kill?
做好牺牲的准备了吗?
Are you ready to die?
如果这个谈判是一个骗局
If this negotiation is a trick,
我们立马杀出去
we start killing immediately.
立马
Immediately.
我们可以低空飞越红海
We can fly down over the Red Sea
以躲开受到敌方雷达的检测
at low level to avoid enemy radar.
最后一架飞机在23:45离开后
When the last plane leaves at 23:45,
跑道灯继续保持开启15分钟
the runway lights stay on for 15 minutes.
-那是我们的突破口 -嗯
- That's our window. - Mm.
乌干达士兵没有什么威胁性
The Ugandan soldiers have nothing at stake.
他们一旦看到我们抵达
Once they see us when we get there,
-他们就会吓得逃跑 -等一下
- they will start running. - Just a second there.
你说你没有足够的燃油 对吧?
You said you didn't have enough fuel, right?
这至关重要
This is crucial.
对 我们得在回来的路上重新加油
Yeah, we're gonna have to refuel on our way back home.
长官 我们可以在肯尼亚加油
Sir, Kenya will be the best place to do it.
莫塔
Motta.
这项行动不会成功的
This operation is not gonna succeed.
这简直在胡闹好吗? 这...这简直是在做梦
This is a charade, okay? This... it's fantasy.
德国人分裂了犹太人
The Germans separated the Jews.
做出选择 莫塔
Selection, Motta.
我们不能白白坐在这儿什么也不干
We can't just sit here, do nothing.
那些是我的手下
These are my men.
如果他们死了就是我的责任
If they die, it's my responsibility.
不 莫塔 他们是以色列士兵
No, Motta. They are Israeli soldiers.
那是总理的责任
It's the prime minister's responsibility.
莫塔 你会支持我吗?
Are you going to back me up on this, Motta?
第六日
1976年 7月2日 星期五
-早上好 -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
他们在谈判
They're negotiating.
你觉得他们会召回你吗?
You think they're gonna call you back?
我不觉得这项行动会被批准 但是...
I don't think the operation's gonna be approved, but...
我们得训练
we have to practice.
为什么非得是你?
Why does it have to be you?
我们就此谈过多少次了?
How many times are we gonna talk about this?
我们不能一直处于战争状态
We can't just be at war all the time.
你没有一直处于战争状态 你是一个舞者
You're not at war all the time. You're a dancer.
我战斗所以你能跳舞
I fight so you can dance.
如果我不跳舞了呢?
What if I stop dancing?
喂
Yeah.
冷静
Calm down.
安静 安静
Quiet, quiet.
听着
Listen.
以色列政府已经同意谈判了
The Israeli government has agreed to negotiate.
截止日期已经延长至周日上午11:00
The deadline has been extended until 11:00 a.m. on Sunday.
为表好意
As a gesture of goodwill,
我们已经释放了所有的法国公民
we have released all French nationals.
接着一旦我们的同志被释放
And then, once our comrades are freed,
你们都会重获自由
you will all be free.
你们现在可以回到大房间了
You can go back to the big room now.
快点
Come on.
以色列从来不会谈判
Israel never negotiates.
-大家快点 -不
- Come on, everyone. - No.
我们不能走
这是道德准则
和乘客待在一起是我们的职责
直到最后一刻
我明白这不容易
你以为你要去哪里?
Where do you think you are going?
这是写给我妻子的信
This is a letter for my wife.
快点
Hurry up.
能把这封信带给我妻子吗
-好的 先生 -谢谢
- Oui, monsieur. - Merci.
给你
Here.
我来照顾他
I'll take care of it.
快结束了
当然
Yeah.
这是谁?
What is this?
嗯? 应该来个黑人
Huh? It's supposed to be black.
- 嘿 他们肤色只会是黑色 – 当然
- Hey, it's the only color they had. - Yeah.
你在开玩笑是吗?
You gotta be kidding me, right?
我要这里最好的射击手
I want the best shooters of the unit
和我一起坐梅赛德斯执行任务
inside the Mercedes with me.
我们将分成五组突击航站楼
We're gonna raid the terminal in five teams.
约书亚领导第一组
Joshua will lead the first team.
穆基领导第二组
Muki, second team.
齐夫领导第三组
Zeev, third team.
阿莫斯和埃雷兹分别领导第四组和第五组
Amos and Erez, fourth and fifth.
我们在新航站楼跑道上登陆
We're gonna land here in the new terminal runway,
一直到这里
all the way to here.
分坐一辆梅赛德斯和两辆路虎出发
We're gonna go out in one Mercedes and two Land Rovers.
开向旧航站楼
We're gonna drive all the way to the old terminal.
停在塔下
We're gonna park under the tower,
躲避狙击手
hidden from sniper fire.
兵贵神速
Surprise and speed is the key.
总理同意这项任务之后
And if the prime minister approves this mission,
我们就出发
we will go.
恐怖分子只需要
The terrorists only need
几分钟就能杀光所有人
a few minutes to kill everyone.
如果第一架飞机被侦测到并受到攻击
What if the first plane is identified and attacked
在没有支援的情况下怎么处理?
before the rest of the force has time to land and deploy?
他们就没有机会了
They won't stand a chance.
如果这失败了
And if it fails,
对以色列国防军的打击 对以色列的打击 将
the blow to the IDF, to Israel, will be...
是个灾难
catastrophic.
无论如何 我的决定受内阁决定
Anyway, I am bound by the Cabinet's decision.
伊扎克 你就是内阁
Yitzhak, you are the Cabinet.
演习一次
Rehearse it.
他们已经在演习了
They already are.
全都回到原先位置
Everybody back to first position!
我没有看到信号
I didn't see the signal.
给我扩音器
Give me the megaphone.
你第一个上
You're staying first.
你第二个上
You go second.
你在犹豫 又在犹豫
You're hesitating... again.
你断后
You go last.
莫塔
Motta.
我要把这个行动
I'm going to recommend the operation
上报给拉宾和内阁 如果他说这样可行的话
to Rabin and the Cabinet if he says it's okay.
你能成功吗 约尼?
Can you do it, Yoni?
第七日
1976年 7月3日 星期六
有什么会
Is there anything
妨碍到他们解救人质吗?
blocking their path to the hostages?
没有 长官
No, sir.
在航空站不会有任何问题
There are no obstacles around the terminal.
什么都阻挡不了我们解救人质
Nothing to stop our men reaching the hostages.
在他们离开之前 我想合张影
I want the photograph to reach the men before they leave.
谢谢
Thank you.
没有什么能阻碍这次的行动
There's nothing to stop the operation from proceeding.
所以现在你必须做个选择
So now you have to make a decision.
如果我还是上将的话
If I was still a general,
我不会同意这次任务
I would never approve this mission.
这有极大的危险
It's a huge risk.
你们知道的 这件事有非常多的变数
There will be casualties. You all know that.
关于这次的任务不能有任何的犹疑
What we cannot doubt is the mission.
我们必须完成这次任务
We must complete our objective.
我们一定要在三分钟内到达航空站
We need to get to the terminal in three minutes,
把所有恐怖分子解决并解救人质
kill all the terrorists and rescue the hostages.
不能被其他事情阻碍
And we don't stop for nothing
直到所有人质安全
until all the hostages are safe.
我们将起飞到达火力范围
We will take off and get into striking range
在等待内阁的决定时
while we wait for the Cabinet's decision.
出发
Let's go.
所有人上飞机
Everybody on board.
波尼
Boni.
- 总理 - 莫塔
- Prime Minister. - Motta.
总理
Prime Minister.
我的职位在座各位应该都知道
My position is well known to those in this room.
我肯定内阁会支持你的决定
I am sure that the Cabinet will support your decision
承担集体的责任
and take collective responsib...
西蒙 飞机已经起飞了
Shimon, the plane's already left.
我们可以调他们回来 如果内阁决定
We'll call them back if the Cabinet decides
不执行任务
not to proceed with the operation.
莫塔
Motta.
你把这次行动报告给内阁了吗?
Do you recommend this operation to the Cabinet?
是的 总理
Yes, Prime Minister.
先生们 阿莫斯将进行一个陈述
Gentlemen, Amos will now read a statement,
之后我们进行投票
and then we will vote.
政府部门决定
"The government resolves to approve
赞同实施营救任务
"implementation of a rescue operation
由以色列国防军实施
"by the Israeli Defense Forces
解救恩德培的人质
"to free the hostages at Entebbe, according to
依照国防部门
"the plan submitted by the defense minister
和参谋长提供的营救计划实施
and the chief of staff."
在座各位是否支持?
All those in favor?
那就这样行动
So be it.
雷霆行动按计划执行
Operation Thunderbolt will proceed as planned.
特拉维夫指挥中心
Tel Aviv Command Center,
雷霆行动开始
Thunderbolt is a go.
重复 雷霆行动开始
I repeat, Thunderbolt is a go.
预计到达恩德培时间为
ETA, Entebbe...
２３：４５
23:45
减四小时 32
Minus four hours, 32.
那是我们的通道
That's our door.
是控制塔的第四层
It's the fourth from the control tower.
胡安·帕布洛
Juan Pablo...
我真希望和你待在家
I wish I was at home with you.
我真希望我在家
I wish I was at home.
我不知道我的家在哪里
I don't know where my home is.
当这些过去之后我们需要一个家
Think we need to find a home when this is over.
在某个地方
Somewhere.
和平的地方
Somewhere peaceful.
贾贝尔认为以色列军会来
Jaber thinks the Israelis will come
并且会杀了我们
and they'll kill us.
如果这真的发生 我们必须说出我们的想法
And then if that happens, we have to make a statement.
这是我们在这里的原因
And that's why we are here.
我在担心博斯
I'm worried about Bose.
他在害怕
He's scared.
你知道的 他很脆弱
He is weak. You know that.
他们都很害怕
They're all scared.
贾贝尔也是
Even Jaber.
我不害怕
I'm not scared.
我看清了
I see it.
现在我看清了所有事情
I see everything now.
我想你可能是对的
I think maybe you were right.
但是如果我没有来这里
But if I never came here,
那又意味着什么?
what would that mean?
不 你帮不上忙
No, there's nothing you can do.
任何人都帮不上忙
There's nothing anyone can do.
没有人能逃出去
There's no escape.
没有人
No escape.
或许我就不应该来
I think maybe I shouldn't have come.
- 或许我就不应该来 – 女士
- I think maybe I shouldn't have come... - Miss.
这些电话都没用了
Those phones are not working.
那里还有电话
There are other telephones over there.
再见 胡安·帕布洛
Good-bye, Juan Pablo.
如果任务失败 把这个递交上去
If the mission fails, submit it.
您认为的任务失败是什么呢 总理?
And what's your definition of failure, Prime Minister?
25位人质在马洛特死亡 这是个灾难
25 hostages died at Ma'alot, and it was a disaster.
这一次 营救25人左右就是成功
This time around, 25 or less will be a success.
你早该走了
走？
去哪
去丛林吗
不 我在想胡安·帕布洛
他不适合这次行动
需要我们最优秀的两个人
对不起
胡安·帕布洛是对的
我想来这
我想来
现在情况怎么样?
What's the status?
最后一架民用飞机刚起飞
Last civilian flight just took off.
应该在十分钟内着陆
Should be landing in ten minutes.
用无线电通信情况怎么样?
How about the radio communication?
有许多干扰 但是能够联系上
There's lots of static, but they're getting through.
因此 目前来说 还不错
So... so far, so good.
好的 先生们
Okay, gentlemen.
情况就是这样
This is it.
到了
Okay.
我们突击航站楼时
As soon as we hit the terminal,
你们开始射击控制塔
you start shooting the control tower.
- 好  – 你明白了吗?
- Okay. Yeah. - Yes?
兵贵神速
Surprise and speed is the key.
出发
Here we go.
他们开枪了
They are reporting gunfire.
现在太早了不能开枪
It's too early for gunfire.
停下
Stop.
是阿明吗?
Is that Amin?
无论发生什么
Whatever happens...
我们做的是对的事情
...we did the right thing.
- 是以色列兵 – 关上门
- It's the Israelis. - Cover the door.
关上门!
Cover the doors!
行动!
Go, go, go!
我们得杀了他们
我来
趴下
Get down.
所有人趴下!
Everybody, get down!
穆基 走
Muki, go.
走
Go.
大卫 进门!
David, take the door!
- 以色列兵 所有人趴下 – 前进
- IDF! Everybody down! - Move forward!
前进!前进!
Move forward! Move forward!
所有人趴下!
Everybody down!
- 前进!前进! – 停!停止射击
- Move forward! Move forward! - Stop! Don't shoot!
- 停 – 人质在这里 人质
- Stop! - Hostage! Hostage!
手榴弹!
Grenade!
我们在飞机上
We are in the air.
我们安全营救了102位人质
We have 102 hostages safe on board.
重复 我们安全营救了102位人质
I repeat, we have 102 hostages safe on board.
总理 祝贺你 你成功了
Congratulations on your success, Prime Minister.
我们拯救了一百多人的生命
We saved a hundred lives.
我们应当为此感到自豪
And we should be proud of that.
西蒙,但是如果我们没有协商成功的话
But if we cannot negotiate, Shimon,
这场战争将永不会停止
this war will never end.
因为劫机去世的四位人质：
让-雅克·米默尼 艾达·布洛维茨 帕斯科·科恩 朵拉·布洛赫
45名乌干达士兵 5名巴基斯坦人 2名德国人 也在恩德培行动中去世
1995年 总理伊扎克·拉宾在签署了以色列与巴勒斯坦的和平协议后被一名犹太极端分子刺杀
西蒙·佩雷斯在之后开始支持与巴勒斯坦和平谈判
他于2016年因高龄去世
约拿森·内塔尼亚胡上校是唯一战死的以色列士兵
他的弟弟在他死后踏入政坛
并在1996年当上总理
至今 以巴两国再无和平谈判
2018年3月